Jeanne M. Pindar Hampton Beach NH 603-205-2159 work@jpindar.com

I am an embedded systems designer who has worked primarily in the rf industry, and has experience with the full software & firmware development cycle as well as hands-on experience in electronics manufacturing.

While most of my experience has been with embedded systems and with automating test equipment, I am also interested in other types of hardware and software development. I have experience with remote work, and I have a distraction-free work environment including a basic electronics lab. I am able to work any shift or timezone.

SKILLS

Git, SVN, Linux, DOS, Bash, command line, shell scripting

C, Python, Java, HTML/CSS/JS

Bare-metal firmware, unit testing, static analysis, board bring up, debugging

Digital circuit design, including microcontrollers (mostly Microchip PIC processors)

Schematic capture and PCB layout

Single Board Computers and industrial mcu boards

Communications protocols and interfaces such as GPIB (HPIB, IEEE-488), USB, SPI, I2C, UART (RS232, RS-485, RS-422), TCP/IP, UDP

Automation of test equipment such as network analyzers, spectrum analyzers, oscilloscopes, signal generators etc.

Testing, calibrating, and troubleshooting digital, analog, and rf circuits

Experience working with legacy code and older languages and with porting applications between languages/platforms Soldering, building prototypes, test fixtures, cables etc.

Personal experience: Rust, Raspberry Pi, Beaglebone, Arduino / Atmel, SDR, IOIO, Unity3D, Virtual Worlds (OpenSimulator), Android

WORK HISTORY

TelGaAs Inc. O'Fallon, MO Jun 2017 - Nov 2019

This was a fully remote contract

Designed microcontroller boards; drew schematics and laid out PCBs

Wrote bare metal firmware in C; configured network modules for IoT products

Performed testing, tuning, and component level troubleshooting of active microwave filter circuits and digital circuits Analyzed and plotted test data

Provided remote support of coworkers and customers with updating firmware, configuring and troubleshooting systems etc.

Wrote documentation

SimWave RF & Microwave Design, Londonderry, NH (now part of TelGaAs Inc.) Feb 2015 - Jun 2017

This was a partially remote position

Designed microcontroller boards; drew schematics and laid out PCBs

Specified and purchased electronic components, circuit boards and subassemblies

Wrote bare metal firmware in C: Configured network modules for IoT products

Implemented computer-controlled calibration and testing of products for increased speed and accuracy

Designed and programmed both GUI and command line software to control products and development boards and to acquire and analyze data from test instruments

Analyzed and plotted test data

Wrote scripts to automate GUIs and to automate remote testing of embedded devices

Performed testing, tuning, component level troubleshooting and repair of active microwave devices, and various digital and analog circuits

Built prototypes, test fixtures, cables etc.

Wrote documentation

Q-Filter Products (a division of Bartley Machine Co.) Amesbury MA Nov. 2006 - Jan. 2015 Designed Microchip PIC processor based embedded systems and other circuits

Drew schematics and laid out PCBs

Specified and purchased electronic components, circuit boards and subassemblies

Wrote bare-metal firmware in C; configured network modules for IoT products

Wrote desktop software to control products and instrumentation

Wrote Java applets to control IoT devices

Implemented computer-controlled calibration and testing of products for increased speed and accuracy

Performed testing, tuning, component level troubleshooting and repair of active microwave filter circuits and other rf devices, and various digital and analog circuits

Analyzed and plotted test data in Excel

Wrote documentation

Built prototypes, test fixtures, cables etc.

Micronetics Inc., Hudson NH (now part of Mercury Systems) 1999 - 2005

Designed, programmed, and implemented instrument control systems using PC's, embedded computers, and various GPIB and serial instrumentation

Performed testing, tuning, component level troubleshooting and repair of active microwave filter circuits and other rf devices, and various digital and analog circuits using network analyzers, spectrum analyzers, oscilloscopes, power meters and other instruments;

Wrote firmware in C and assembly language

Wrote software in Pascal and Visual Basic, ported software from HP Basic and other obsolete languages

Wrote Acceptance Test Procedures and other documentation

Built prototypes, test fixtures, cables etc.

Vectronics Microwave Corporation, Middlesex NJ (now part of Mercury Systems) 1985 - 1999

Designed, programmed, and implemented ATE systems using PC's, Hewlett Packard computers, and various HPIB and analog instruments;

Implemented computer-controlled calibration and testing of products for increased speed and accuracy Tested and calibrated active microwave devices using network and spectrum analyzers, oscilloscopes, and other instruments;

Designed, prototyped, tested and performed component level repair of various digital and analog circuits such as interfaces (IEEE-488, RS-232-C, etc.), amplifiers, and voltage controlled oscillators; Built prototypes, test fixtures, cables etc.

EDUCATION

Trenton State College, Trenton NJ, majored in Physics University of Scranton, Scranton PA, majored in Engineering Science